# JONATHAN T. BAY, PHR, SHRM-CP

www.linkedin.com/in/jonnybay/

801.674.5971 jonny.bay@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Dependable, organized, and honest Human Resource professional with credible track record of high-quality performance. Experienced in change management, onboarding, recruiting, training, and leading projects. Effective communicator, capable of handling multiple responsibilities and departments. MBA degree and PHR/SHRM-CP certification.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

iDRIVE FULFILLMENT, Draper, UT

2020-2023

#### **DevOps Manager**

Manage a team of warehouse tech support individuals. Interact with customers to resolve issues and understand new development requests. Work on integrations with EDI and other platforms. Create SQL and JavaScript rules. Gather Development requirements. Write reports. Set up new customers.

#### iDRIVE FULFILLMENT, Draper, UT

2018 - 2020

### Warehouse Tech Support

Work with internal and external teams to understand needs for development and present requirements to developers. Use SQL to write reports and make database updates.

### iDRIVE FULFILLMENT, Draper, UT

2017 - 2018

#### Team Lead

Resolve client issues and concerns. Ensure safe productive warehouse environment. Oversee a team of warehouse associates. Train staff. Ensure high productivity.

- Liaison between new clients and warehouse staff to ensure proper product organization and presentation.
- Successfully on boarded 3 new clients from March to June 2018.

### ROSEMAN UNIVERSITY OF HEALTH SCIENCES, South Jordan, UT

2016 - 2017

#### **Human Resource Generalist**

Responsible for HR Operations on the South Jordan, Utah campus. Responsibilities include recruiting, assisting with HR Project implementations, employee on-boarding and out-processing, leave administration. Create, update, and maintain job descriptions. Review compensation related to FLSA and duties. Prepare reports, and serve as member of the Campus Leadership Team.

- Redesigned the recruitment process reducing time to hire by 40%.
- Provide high level of customer service. Resolve concerns and issues of employees and HR department vendors.
- Responsible to onboard all new employees. Follow through on onboarding program and milestones.
- Assisted with implementation of ADP Workforce Now system update for 600 employees, including running reports and auditing information for accuracy and consistency.
- Moved open enrollment process to an electronic system decreasing enrollment errors by an estimated 75%, helping with the change management by communicating with employees and teaching them how to use our employee self-serve portal.
- Restructured dental assistants after review of compensation showing they were underpaid.

### **Human Resource Leader**

Provided day-to day support to managers and employees in all aspects of Human Resources. Responsibilities included: recruiting, training and development, compensation, benefits, employee/management coaching, legal compliance, policy creation, and payroll processing. Oversaw strategic vision of HR department and managed office operations.

- Implemented new payroll processing system and software, Lathem; reducing time to process payroll by 50% and improving record accuracy. An excel file was created to migrate data to the new system.
- Refined search process to effectively recruit for Master Estheticians with sales experience.
- Planned and orchestrated annual kick off training meetings by soliciting feedback from employees on topics and methods of desired learning and creating individual development plans for the year.
- Created sales commission plan for inside sales team resulting in increased monthly sales.
- Decreased turn-over rate by 23%.

JONATHAN T. BAY, PHR

JONNY.BAY@GMAIL.COM

Page Two

### ARGOSY UNIVERSITY, Draper, UT

2008 - 2013

### **Human Resource Generalist / Manager**

Managed all HR activities at Salt Lake Campus. Facilitated on-boarding, recruitment, orientation, wellness, performance management and reviews. Assisted with terminations and employee relations issues. Resource for employee benefits and oversaw payroll for staff and faculty. Member of campus Executive Team. Managed facilities and IT operations.

- Achieved 100% compliance on mandatory training for faculty and staff 4 years in a row. Accomplished by tailoring the training to each individual's preferred learning style.
- Recipient of corporate Focus on People Award for 4 consecutive years.
- Organized campus outreach events to strategically promote company brand and awareness, resulting in 15% increased lead flow.
- Implemented processes and procedures to prepare campus for full scale internal compliance audit. Received score of 4.2 out of 5, highest score for any campus to date.
- Provided IT support to campus. Became self-taught tier 1 support expert on campus. Used Altiris to image new computers. Set up classroom computers and implemented new software on them.

### BYU PERFORMING ARTS MANAGEMENT, Provo, UT

2007 - 2008

#### **Administrative Assistant**

Prepared reports for all regional shows under Performing Arts Management jurisdiction. Contacted presenters on a regular basis to maintain relationships and coordinated / facilitated performing group tours. Created itineraries and plans for group tours. Assisted administration in duties as assigned.

- Organized over 40 successful performance tours for artistic groups, resulting in profit for both BYU and hosting associations.
- Utilized Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to create materials for tour manuals.

#### **SKILLS AND CAPABILITIES**

Speak, read, and write Conversational Portuguese
Expert in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, Powerpoint).

Knowledge of Adobe Illustrator, Slack, OneNote, Procreate, Photoshop (limited)
Have used: Lawson, Kronos, ADP, Lathem, Wave accounting, BlueBox

#### TRAINING COURSES TAUGHT

Performance Management, Communication at EDMC Getting Ready, Business Ethics Policy and Code of Conduct, Time Management

## Adjunct Faculty, Business Negotiation and Conflict Management, Undergraduate course (2013)

### **EDUCATION**

Professional in Human Resources Certification (**PHR**) **MBA**, Argosy University, Draper, UT **BA**, Humanities, English Emphasis, Business Minor, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT

### **VOLUNTEER**

Board Member of Human Resources Association of Central Utah, HRACU (2014-2016)